

SAEID NOROOZI

BACKEND SOFTWARE ENGINNER

https://s-noroozi-cs.github.io/

OBJECTIVE

Working as a Backend-Developer for 10+ years, makes Saeid expert engineer in software industry. He is quite keen on learning new technologies and innovation. Besides, his experience is full of architectural challenges such as performance tuning, scaling, failover, etc. He has great experiences in CI / CD and automation.

EXPERIENCE

Backend Software Engineer

Informatics Services co, Tehran, December 2018 – Present

- Design, develop and tune multiple software modules for payment switches using Spring-boot (Web, Data, Security, Cloud ...) stacks.
- Scaling application by Microservices architecture and Streaming data pipeline with Apache Kafka.
- Adding resiliency and fault tolerance by implementing Circuit Breaker and Retry patterns with Resilience4j library.
- Using GraalVM to create native, light and efficient cloud services.
- Securing communication by JWT and JWS.
- Using Junit and Cucumber for test scenarios.
- Streaming all system and application logs to Kafka and preprocessing them with Logstash.
- Containerized with Docker and orchestrated with kubernetes.
- Using Oracle as database and Redis as cache server.
- Using GitLab for CI / CD and Google-Error-Prone to check quality.

Backend Software Engineer

GAM Electronics co, Tehran, April 2012 – November 2018

- Maintenance, customize and improvement Document Management System and Workflow engines.
- Developing based on Java EE stack EJB, JPA, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, JMS, Servlet, Filter
- Integrate different software modules with Central Authentication Service (CAS) old and new version together.
- Writing Linux shell script to automate task such as managing our application servers, deployment modules and etc.
- Writing Ant tasks to automate build of legacy system modules.
- Tuning SQL queries for critical reports.

CONTACTS



s.noroozi.cs@gmail.com



+989128612696



TEHRAN - IRAN

MEDIA



s-noroozi-cs



saeid-noroozi

SKILLS

lava

Microservices

Spring boot

Apache Kafka

Docker

Cloud Native

GitLab CI / CD

UNIX / Linux Shell Scripting

SQL

EDUCATION

BS, Software Engineering, 2005 -2010 Tehran, Iran

Languages

Persian Azerbaijani Turkish English

Birth Date

2nd December 1986